let's get started
uh so a couple uh Logistics uh before we
start uh so uh I do hopefully have been
in on the slack workspace uh We've
nailed down the time slots a lot of
times a lot for the section is down to
three time slots but you have to vote uh
so uh we're trying to find the time that
that's uh most suitable but uh uh well
thank you that appeal will not be able
to make the time but the sections will
be recorded uh and uh also
um you know if you uh you know the
office hours uh are posted in the
updated syllabus but that's more
flexible and uh you know
a question is an economic to my office
hour you can always always feel free to
next time sure
um
um okay so uh this lecture uh and the
next uh couple uh lectures will be about
lagrantian formalism
uh for uh fun mechanics
uh well this is a preparation for uh the
study of genuine Quantum field theories
um but uh you know actually a lot of the
technologies that were really
the most clearly explained in a simple
model mechanics which will do that
um which we'll do first
um so
um
[Music]
uh let's recall uh in uh classical
mechanics
[Music]
uh and then there's the hamiltonian
foreign
formalism
um
we can talk about uh the state of
classical system and again that is
characterized by the coordinates uh and
in time derivative of time uh I'm going
to most
um
could be some general coordinates for
Alpha Atomic index that went from one to
an if you have a system and equate the
freedom hopefully this is uh uh uh not
unfamiliar from classical mechanics
I think
uh but the point is the important things
in the state description
any questions about this yes
uh we have uh the state is
the alphas are uh the uh canonical
momenta uh conjugates to these two
um now in the case of uh uh you know
three particles a moving space
what's your momentum but if you can't
generalize coordinates then P into
quality some generalized motion is
hundreds of years
uh now
um
um so
and then we need to describe hand
Evolution and that's that's the job of
mechanics uh so uh the question uh the
timely Evolution will be characterized
by its own equation of motion
the action
um
action
uh probably you know oh no that's what
that means and
um okay uh in the hematology problem on
the other hand uh we can write the
equation of motion of any uh that I
expected that the time is derivative
because of Any quantity let's say f is
some uh
and the question is
brackets
um how many of you know when the person
bracket is
so for example uh
uh qdot is a pH live
yeah
um
uh okay so
uh let's see
and um now of course these two problems
uh are supposed to be equivalent for the
standard form of the lagrangian or the
hamiltonian so these are lagrangea
definitely is
they're related by
um
minus l
and this will be evaluated uh at um
the solution to the equation
could be out by the Alpha dot which is
the same at the position that the
extreme Idols to the right hand side
with the direct to computer
difference
uh so hopefully you have all seen this
before uh are there any questions uh
before we move to Quantum Mechanics
that's interesting a reminder of that
classical mechanics and the relation in
hamiltonian and laguential problems
any questions
okay yeah
um why is hamiltonian like P Alpha like
lower interest required
uh in what sense are they dual uh uh
good question so um uh one way just to
say is is because
the position bracket
uh so the Muslim bracket
which is
two changes and G until q and this is
defined to be uh because he might be
mentioned
Alpha minus uh the one with f and g
switch
um
imagine this
um uh and uh
to the structure of this hamiltonian
system uh in fact you know the the
hamiltonian system is only a Divine
provided that you specify that the
poisson structure which is parameters
now the point is that uh I think
probably in your uh you know freshman
mechanics course when you first learn
this kind of thing you start then you
start with it very quickly you are
LeBron James as a way to rewind
lagrangea LaGrange equation
um but once you're casting you no longer
need to think about the Q dots right so
so run your bonus of you as it's
familiar and if you do this is
Data System you've only talk about
computers
any other questions
uh all right so uh now let's talk about
mechanics
uh so now it's about quantum mechanics I
think
um so uh important mechanics
um
uh well usually probably more familiar
with the hamiltonian
um so uh
uh we have that was speak of the state
um let's say
uh kit so this is a statement very fun
builderspace this discarding age this is
the the Hilbert space
um of uh physical States
in a product and support
um and uh uh uh
you don't know and if you want to
um
promote a classicism component system
and through the procedure of
colonization and you uh and this H into
some operator and Page hat uh by
replacing p and Q with a p huge hat
um and you replace the bottom bracket by
probably the appropriate commentators
according to the economic communication
commutation
um
uh now um
so
um
and uh of course uh I do well no uh the
state can be specified equivalent
equality specified in terms of the wave
functions
um and then we can speak up I'm
evolution
uh
which is uh
um
characterized by a unitary operator
that's called a uh P that represents
time evolution by the amount of time T
and this can be written as individual
convention e to the minus I over H bar
the hamiltonian times
operator
um and uh of course um then you know
that there are two different ways to
Android time Evolution I'll show you the
picture uh in which uh the state
themselves uh transform the kind of
evolution but actually
viewer okay
um alternatively in the Heisenberg
picture which is uh more convenient for
most of our considerations
um I can break picture you post the
state fixed
and instead you evolve all the operators
uh the correspondent observables uh
under time Evolution uh conjugation so
operative o and the time Evolution get
transformed to all uh multiplying by
deleting on the right and the UT inverse
on the left
um and at this quantity I'm going to
design it to be o of P so instead of
talking about the state uh evolving in
time we'll be talking about operating
moving time these are the kind of
operators who's not in the state will be
our physical observatives
um and uh of course the consequence of
this
[Music]
um
we were here is a consequence of of this
uh
um it is a consequence of this that um
the time derivative
of this operator defining it this way uh
it's a easy uh computation
and this is the inside analog of that
equation uh just with the possible
bracket replaced by the commentator and
within factors I and h y
um okay so uh so that's a quick recap of
quantum mechanics in hematology problem
uh the state and time even though any
questions
okay so
um uh hopefully that's all familiar to
you uh and now let's discuss the uh
lagrangia
uh formism and quantum mechanics
um so another one you come to the
Quality mechanics uh
what is like one Republican point of
attendance how do you do that uh well
um uh this is uh
uh you know this is really done through
the pathogen
um
I think probably uh most of you have
seen the path we were before uh but uh
may not feel I'm not sure if everyone
feels comfortable with it so I'm going
to discuss this in some detail because
the pandemic was going to be an
essential tool in the formulation of
quantum field Theory uh and we're gonna
spend the time trying to uh you know to
be uh to be solid with this in one
mechanics and as you see it's actually
pretty untrivial even in very simple
amount of quantum mechanics and there
are many solarities associated with it
um which will which is why we're going
to spend a little time on that uh so in
order to form the quantum mechanics uh
through the lagrangian
um and we're going to work with the
action
uh this action is still of the possible
form so
um whenever we use the so you see uh in
the classical mechanics of course H and
L are both this functions of these
variables
um but in quantity candidates would like
to promote H to an operator there's no
operator that corresponds to the ground
here okay so the quantum mechanics of
lagrangea instead of the ground Gym
LaGrange is still a classical concept is
there some ordinary function no q and Q
dot still no difference uh all right
um
so uh uh so how do we do quantum
mechanics uh in this language uh well
the uh the claim is that um if you want
to characterize so first of all let's
start with that
um some basis of States let's say uh if
I write uh Q uh KET this means uh that
this is the is the
Q uh
um hat eigenstate
you know
um all right so this when I came out of
the Alpha Zone the operating this is
on the right hand side is the eigenvalue
is infected but operator can you think
of some particle
um and say uh
the simplest example of course
the positive examples would be this L if
we
um
potential describing
yeah um describing particle uh uh
properties and potential and moving some
potential and
um
the quantizer system you expect to have
some hamiltonian in the usual form
um the San Antonio would be
is the
uh
and a plus v
few hats
um and uh here I'm going to be talking
about the eigen state uh we're back with
two hat Market that's the usual story
but now I want to
formulate uh the system purely in the
language of the lagrangian without
appealing to the hamiltonian so how do
we do that
um
to do that
well first let me write on the formula
for the path integral
um
perhaps most of you have seen this
formula but we're going to go to its
derivation and discuss all right and
discuss how to use it
so
um we're going to be interested in The
Matrix elements of the time Evolution
operator in a sense uh this you know
because this queue basis will form this
complete basis of our Uber space in the
typical I mean simple I mean volume
system like like this uh if you
characterize all the Matrix Elemental
time you build operator you know
everything about the time evolution in
principle uh so here uh this uh
subscript I stands for initial and the f
is final so I have some initial State
and some final State these are state of
my arbitrary Choice okay so I'm not
saying that the state here I will evolve
into qf I'm not saying that at all I'm
just picking some arbitrary basis States
uh Qi there's qis these have eigenvalue
Qi Alpha with back to this operators
Cube I Alpha hat and these have some
eigenvalue Alpha we're back to this
queue
of a hat operator uh and this UT is the
time Evolution operator uh I was talking
about over there
it's pretty good capital T for the total
amount of time of evolution and again uh
let me remind you that we're going to be
working in the high temperature so and
the primary uh only operator is
gonna evolve according to that equation
over there the state will be how it's
based uh but in any case this the state
is the way this is some fixed record
number space and this we're just talking
about the Matrix elements of the time
Evolution operator
okay and the statements of that integral
is a representation uh it's a formula
like this it says that this thing is
supposed to be some kind of integral of
e to the I over H Bar times the action
uh this action is going to be
evaluated so I never wrote the limits of
the integral here uh so here in this
context there's action it's going to be
defined by integrated from zero to T DT
of L
so this is filled as a functional of uh
so this is
um as a functional
of a view of githat for T ranging
between uh zero and the capital T let's
say
um
and um so this s is viewed as a function
of the skill uh and we're going to going
to be perform an integration over the
space of functions uh Q of T whatever
that is
um what is an appropriate measure which
we'll discuss
and the subject the boundary condition
that Q uh at the initial time which is
equal to zero is equal to Qi and Q at
the final time which is a equal to qf
and that's at least heuristically is how
what the pathway is supposed to be and
what it does for you
uh any questions about this
yes
uh well how would you promote lagrangeas
to an operator uh there's no there's no
rule for what you do with that
I can tell you a function of the
canonical variable cubes and teams and
the rule is to promote the queue that
people operators and replaceable bracket
with accommodate
the textbooks there are no rules avoided
with two jobs and they did we don't do
anything with it you simply say that
once you have promoted excuse MPS to
operators the time Evolution indicated
by this this equation which is an analog
of a straightforward analog positive
questions if you buy the appropriate
versions
but it's not obvious uh problem
to coupon mechanics this classically
what you do is extremise them with
action right so so we want to find the
quantum analog of that and and as you
might know have heard of the quantum
analog of that is instead of two
instead of extremizing the action you
want to uh
integrate into that
action or into the io British bar and
action with some appropriate measure
now this uh so how many do I have seen
this formula I've written here
okay how many people know how this is
derived
is likely not quite correct
um in fact if you think about it
um uh how can this really be how can
this be exactly be true uh since
um you know
you know ambiguities when we promote uh
the class we haven't turned into the
bottom we have to tell you right there's
operators to worry about in general so
this Edge could be something
um and uh you know it doesn't have to be
uh simple like that for example if you
take the lagrangian of a 3D Rigid body
and try to come here for that it's not
of that simple form and um uh and in
fact you will have to uh in that case
you know this quadratic Terminal B was
some cooperation that depend on Q
operation
uh so who tells you what the operator
wonder you should be using
now in this Library there is a speaker
so it sounds like there's some ambiguity
that's it's not there is about this
there is another problem
information
uh yes
yes for example
um yeah I mean you know yeah and you
know generally uh it's always possible
to actually some operative order H bar
and some small coefficient and limit
zero that we would just go away you know
all the uh quality ambiguity are going
to be of that form just by demanding you
know it if I take uh some you know
polynomial expression let's say in p's
and q's and people be having two hands
there are many different ways of water
just when you make the result is her
Mission doesn't fix the answer at all
foreign
[Music]
um
uh the cubes themselves
uh and then that's generally going to be
the case
um uh and uh so so you know
we're gonna transformed into the
hamiltonian you'll also find the
quadratic term in the piece uh we'll
have some coefficient that depend on the
cubes
all right
um yeah uh uh after all uh that would
not be the case because there is no if
you have a really rigid body right
there's no potential there's a bunch of
companies zero and the whole thing is
just a kinetic term so you cannot
possibly be something like just you know
some of Cuda squared you know because as
you might know the actual rotational
motion but pretty pretty rotating 3D
Rigid body it's not so Criminal
um okay any other questions
okay so as I said uh in Vermilion
classical system the quantum system and
Hamilton there can be some ambiguity
after all I'm always free to add some
for the page terms for the hamiltonian
nobody can stop me from doing that and
the informally the limit with respect to
zero I'll reduce the same classical
hamiltonian a quantity of course are
different systems uh where would this
kind of ambiguity come from in the uh
lagrangian formalism uh well to
understand that uh well uh you know you
just need to go back and look at the
derivation and see what is wrong with
derivation and of course
um there's some uh maybe the element in
the room is you know what what the heck
is this thing here all right so so we're
going to spend some time discussing that
we're going to revisit or introduce the
derivation of this one
we're going to discuss
um uh what is a measure is or how you
should understand it and that's uh in
some sense where all the suddenly is
hidden uh and uh um there's the zombie
that goes into how you define this
measure is related to the issue with the
so-called regularization uh
regionalization kind of terms and all
that all these things together it really
all has to do with how you define this
measure foreign
make sure
um okay so let's review so we're going
to look at the time Evolution from zero
to time C and I'm going to divide this
and so uh with many slats
um uh and uh that's all we're here seven
times zero we are starting with the
state uh who's uh that is I guess they
went back to the Cubes but you had
argument is Qi we end up with the state
when I United Nations are so the
position where the coordinates move from
Qi to qf
um and uh yeah we're going to at every
type of time Evolution we're going to
insert a complete basis associated with
some
um uh position United States with the
positive q1 and Q2 and Q3 uh and some
support in terms of the explicit formula
and what we'll do is that we're going to
take this Matrix elements of the time
Evolution operator
I'm going to rewrite this importantly in
one way
so the uh let me use capital D for the
number of degrees of freedom and the
number of cues so if you want
um
the the Hue uh n minus one so here I'm
assuming that their end of this time
intervals are equally spaced in time so
this is T divided by n
Okay so
um
Evolution I'll just write an explicit
form of the appendicular version
operator e to the minus sign over H bar
uh
by the amount T Over N that represents
this step of the time Evolution and then
I'm inserting this Q uh n minus one okay
uh and then we have
two minus one
and so on support and finally we have a
q1
uh
okay so this is of course the identity
uh so far this is I've not made any
approximation
um
uh and uh and so there's more
convenience of notation uh let me uh
Define this could be qn and this Qi I'm
gonna call it q0 so I can write a more
uniform expression or this is equal to
uh integral of a product of the few
little n little n random one so
n minus one two
in plus one minus transportation
are there any questions about this
foreign
okay so
um let's uh let's look at this
expression over here
uh so that expression over here
uh this is one term by itself can be
written in that I'm gonna insert a
complete basically like these and that's
right uh V uh D and uh there's some
standard normal addition factor to Pi H
Bar D
um
now this is due to uh monolithic
convention for the standards momentum
basis which you probably all have seen
many times
Q then plus one so I'm really insert in
here uh p n
r uh but the normalization is such that
integral of the cube
Q
the one the insertion is is a factor of
time which part is
a convention it's such that the Q of an
a is going to be into the I which are a
few thoughts
um
any questions about this
so I I so far I haven't still haven't
done anything this is just all kind of
identities I'm just rewriting the whole
thing to this integral and the term in
this product itself is a situation in
the end in this one
any questions
so this as we said is uh this is the
wave function of the
State uh the the
end so this is the wave function the
same way
sorry well this is q a dots PN
Alpha indices
okay that's still exact uh this is the
the point where we're going to uh make a
approximation
so
um uh well there are several various
ways to to think about this so for
example
um so I think of uh and
goes to Infinity
and large
Over N we're talking about the Matrix
elements of um
one minus
H bar which has a over n
completely
over and squared
it's
all right
um now
um
uh if you're as far
uh if you write H bar in terms of p's
and q's let's say moving on the B is the
left and Q to the right of course you've
got something simple like this you don't
have to worry about ordering but more
generally uh the p's and q's are not
convenience in h and you have to you can
always rearrange the order
um uh in some way uh and if you play it
in order please activity
on the left the keys are on the right so
you can take the B10 to the to the left
to the Q is the act to the right you'll
get the argument
so uh so then uh in that case you can
write this guy as
uh as uh B
uh Q uh well
so so the the overlapping in this is he
brought into the cube that is just e to
the minus I on British bar p n starting
with q n
um sometimes
um uh one minus I over H bar h e n q n
what's up
uh so far so good
any questions
I've taken that into account so so in
other words when I write this H without
the Hat what I mean is that I take this
hat okay
I moved yeah I moved a piece of that
because the right I can get some
combination commentators but the
computers again themselves against the
same very range but you always reduce
numbers every time you commute at the
end of the day you can always write a
chat the operator in the form of
products of B hat and two Hardware P hat
is always on the left if you have always
in that form you replace
and that's the thing I'm calling this
page
so this handle
so now this might give you the both
impression that there's some Secrets
ordering we're on the pieces to the left
right actually there's no such sacred
ordering uh you you'll see why why
that's the case but so far uh that's why
thank you
all right
um so uh to uh summarize uh this whole
thing here uh can be so this everything
in the integrand is back to the DN here
uh can be written as
um
[Music]
let's bring these three things together
I have PM starting with q n plus one
minus q n
maybe I have that uh and I'm going to
rewrite this in the form of explanation
uh as minus h of p n uh n and times T
Over N uh Plus on the highway returns
which I will not
be worried about in a moments why do I
want to write as an exponential is
because the exponential uh will behave
simply on your product so now if I take
this and just multiply them together
turn that probably into sum of the
exponents so that's it will be easier to
manipulate it yes yeah sorry again
uh yes so let me give you an example so
let's say uh you have a term uh Q has a
p hat and Q okay
so once I have done this
by a spot bar and now I'm good so if you
had x to the left it because
Q half x to the right except q u n uh
and then and end up with just some
numbers
so this is now the the term uh if I
replace
[Music]
I'm assuming that uh for the moment
although um I mean you know you could
generate the school on to the Taylor
series
standard
any other questions yes
so how are you like moving the machine
side effects oh all I'm saying is that
uh you know if I take this whole thing's
words uh is going to be you're gonna
swear this so that's not also going to
be up 100 here it's work and so all I'm
saying is that if I replace this one
minus this thing by e to the minus this
thing I'm only making mistake of order T
Over N squared but I mean I made that
mistake to begin with anyway so I'm not
going to worry about that but the reason
that I'm not going to worry about that
really is because later on I'm gonna do
the sum and take a little bit n to a
minute uh all right so for now of course
you cannot drop this term you drop this
term you you're changing the answer
um but uh the claim is going to be for
this climate where they will bring us up
but the client is going to be that in
the limit this capital N Go to infinity
and you can actually ignore this or
ignore this
um but we'll see whether that's really
good
yes
normal
ah uh uh good uh well the thing is the
prescription I gave you so far right you
can work with any age cat I'm just
telling you some way to to to produce
this page out of it I didn't say this H
is the naive pathway expression
uh but I said no I was saying that uh
you know and they're given the classical
system there's no reason why the
so-called quantization has to be unique
there's no a correct reason why there's
a unique the quantum systems that reduce
the cost is between the concepts
any other questions
yeah it's whatever you're just
explanation could be easier to deal with
like the multiplicative that's right I'm
about to do that
uh okay so that's the now
it also works if you have no potential
uh I mean
Q hats and uh
look for essentially any Hamilton
uh but uh for most our purposes uh we're
going to be restricting ourselves to
like around your system with the two
derivative kinetic terms in which case
hamiltonian will always be quadratic in
p uh but the dependent on Q is arbitrary
foreign
okay so let's collect this together so
so this is measurement of the tiny
motion operator is now equal to the
integral uh product little n from one to
capital N minus one the qn to the n and
product again from zero to ten minus one
e and actually there's one extra in the
B compared to the Q as you might see
here
minus two n minus h q n d n
discovered in that way and plus some
terms of other e Over N squared
now
what you see here
going on potentially with ordering so if
I started with some classical H remote
to H hat and but then both in this
procedure this age might different from
the classical expression by something
called H bar just like this here so uh
in principle uh you know if you just use
some naive classical expression there
could be some other H bar correction
that could that could be there but for
the reason I have a snap
there's something to keep in mind
okay
um so uh now
um
okay so if you are a great physicist
like fireman you would uh formally take
the angles to Infinity limit
if you do this in the calculus path of
the class but uh but that's right
um
um uh well we would like to write this
uh and uh in this limit uh you you might
imagine there's qns and pins uh turned
into uh functions of uh the ability
um and um so this
this measure here uh there's something
that instructs you how to integrate over
the space of Q centps as functions
availability
so I'm going to write this as V of Q or
sometimes be a community
but let me surprised that this is
function so
um it's some kind of equation measure
um and let's look at this uh this
exponent
this exponent uh well
um formerly the limit Capital angles
still goes to Divinity uh anything here
is going to be uploaded by N squared
multiplied by the sum well the sum has n
terms and so uh you think now you'd
expect that that people to drop out uh
in the limit uh and go into Infinity uh
and uh and then what are you left with
well
um
uh so uh where that's where it is I over
H bar
um the sum is going to be a
approximation of integral uh the
integral in DT uh from zero to faculty
um and this is going to turn into uh T
at T QT
Dot why is that uh well you know let's
say the step a little end horizontal
time T but then this is approximated by
P of T and this is just the integral of
Q Dot and P over that very small time
step so that's something
it is to become that at least provided
this p n and qns are suppose if that
really Equalization of some uh you know
sufficiently smooth looking function
then this will be true
is
something we'll have to worry about
potentially uh and the second term here
will just be well this is just the Over
N is like you see this reference into
minus h of
foreign
okay so um this is uh formerly the uh
doesn't really know anything the
hamiltonian form of the passenger
formed
of uh with happiness
um
okay so let me make a few comments about
this
um
so as you have seen already
uh so how do we actually make sense of
this instruction well one way to make
centimeters because we go back to that
but really in so far that's how easy
right that's the only thing we know
um so uh you should think of this
uh well this this is right here let's
say this
all right when it comes dropped
um as the true definition at this point
of this pattern right so this is in some
sense a regularization so this is uh
sometimes referred to other than that is
regularization
so
um
uh so
in order to
uh to Define
the the functional measure
requires typically requires
uh regularization
that is uh we don't
really know April and how to integrate
over the space of the functions and
that's not something you learn in the
Calculus class
um when we typically do is to try to
um we can understand this as a do that
some kind of limit that is with for
example we can prefer discretize time
into these steps and we integrated with
each and cues at each uh time step so
that that's uh just going back to the
original formula
uh there are other ways to regularize
which might be more convenient for
project computations and but then you
have to understand what the sense their
equivalents which is not uh which is by
no means obvious
so so what we have done so far is to uh
discretize
uh
um
uh now
um another comment is that uh so okay
but maybe you might say that you know
once you do that you kind of you can
offset
um now of course up to up to that point
it was a true derivation but the last
step there was a bit of 10 way we
started young here
um so you could easily imagine uh some
alternative way to to do this
regularization
um
uh for example
uh you know for example uh what do you
record okay so when we recognize not
only we have to if we didn't say if we
discipline not only we have to replace
and measure by something like that we
also have to turn this expression and
the exponent here into some of this
great sum
uh now we said that okay this guy is an
approximation of this
but who says this has to be PN not b n
plus one
well the way we derived it was indeed PM
uh but if I only stare at this analog
expression uh and I want to guess how to
regularize it how would I know it's the
N is going to be in plus one or the
average between plus one or some other
something else well you don't
okay so that's the problem
um so there seems to be a bit of
a bit of you
uh well well we'll see that this
ambiguity is um uh sometimes a feature
not a bug
[Music]
and I will be able to resolve we'll be
we'll be able to figure out a way to to
resolve uh this ambiguity but in some
sense the part the value resolvements
and beauty is part of the definition of
important Theory from the planning open
review
um so
um in fact uh
uh there's a little bit of discussion I
wrote in the lecture notes that I will
post after the class that I will not
write on the board here which is that it
will turn out that if you you could have
replaced uh you could have repeat the
same direction
um
by
uh
you could have repeated the same
derivation
um
uh with uh
uh
let me see
um exchange if you you could have
repeated the derivation exchanging the
rows of the PS and cubes
um and um in which case uh you see uh if
you exchange the role that p's and q's
uh here Q here and P over here you want
to order you know in this page uh you
want to you want to remove the QQ has to
the left and you have to write after
ordering it as this so in which case you
end up with a with different expressions
for this uh for this age of p and the qn
uh and if you actually do that uh you
end up with something like the TN plus
one here
[Music]
uh the point is that that can be viewed
as a different regularization of the
path integral but it's different
regularization would only be the correct
answer of the time Evolution uh provided
by this this age actually different from
your organization by something of water
H bar
so there's some uh
potentially the order is far
ambiguity uh in here that depends on how
you write about X
uh so let me just write this in words
um so so here press h this contains
uh other h-bar antibodies
um which are
they're tied to the that we would
usually call the scheme of
regularization
is in
so the currency in the present example
the spring and seeing just have to go
with how you break that break down this
into the discrete steps and supporting
the B somewhere insert the cubes
um
um and so if you choose April I choose a
different version of the skin you might
end up with uh in order to produce the
same physics you might have to use a
different age the difference uh by
something like other H bar
the difference is uh called color chart
area
literature
yeah um when you say regular
organization like even giving a measure
to that thing uh I mean both no there's
a there's some measure which eight right
is ill-defined uh I would need to uh
both need to turn this into
um a find limits of integral like like
that one so I could there are other ways
to to to to alternatively integral this
is one way of doing it
um where this is discretizes time uh and
uh but once you do that uh the excuse
and beats are going to be you know
instead of uh continuous it's not a
function to P then now there's a large
set of discrete variables so that might
say the variables uh you also have to
express this in terms of those variables
all right so so when you do that there's
some small ambiguity
now please and you get this amazing to
be a significant level for each bar but
uh they will match it
so of course this Integrity you don't
encounter your undergrading from the
times plus because in icon back it
always starts and you don't never say
one you can't you always start by
writing that one hand however it
actually is once you have the operator
there'll be there's no ambiguity that's
fine uh the only reason I hear when you
have music is because we insist on
formulating in terms of lagrangea why
bother now in a number of these quantum
mechanics is not too important to use
the lagrangian and we don't have to use
our ground if we don't like this and you
don't have to worry about it which is
pretty much which is probably why that
you know you have some of you have seen
the category but you don't really know
so much or care about the derivation
because you don't actually need it in
the simple quantum mechanical models
um the reason that we're going to be
using this kind of problem
is because the lagrangea has equivalent
to have an advantage uh it's easier you
know I'm going to open them to uh to
preserve and passively symmetries such
as the pancreation
so in the hamiltonian formism as I have
been moving into the last lecture is
rather uh the the Commerce symmetry is
obscure uh and uh uh you know what not
only that it's obscure it's not easy to
build the correct communion that has
um that has uh relativism causality
because it just got some generic
interaction terminal hamiltonian the
publishing signal will be instantaneous
as in the case in the generic uh quantum
mechanical models
[Music]
Theory uh and one of the key criteria is
that uh you know we have to respect the
rules of speculativity
um and uh it's possible to work in terms
of organism but it's it's not easy uh
and uh to some extent is easier than the
price you have to pay because you have
to worry about organization and common
terms
uh it's going to be a part of the uh
definition uh you know how you result
ambiguity as I said earlier should be
viewed as a part of the definition of
the quantum theory in this moment
uh now uh in
if you don't have any additional
physical principles like symmetries and
so forth then generally there is no
principle to tell you how to choose the
term of what HR and have it done
um in practice you always determine that
by some additional physical input uh it
turns out that Hungary symmetry
particularly this I mentioned last time
which is a very strong constraint it's
not obvious this moment but we'll see
later on that um uh it's very strongly
strength then very often for large class
the quantum field theories help you to
pronounce goodies down to finally many
possible parameters
yes
yes if you uh that that's right that's
the thing I was you can put the videos
there and insert the cues here right so
I think you can kind of try to do that
and that's presenting the thing I was
measuring if you do that you'll actually
use a different wondering
and why
wow so I I think your question is why is
lebronianism uh why does it why is it
easier to preserve this imagery no it's
not why
it seems
uh well I'm not uh it is a user-friendly
thing I mean it is possible to to
computer without every time I look
around here
it is possible uh it uh slightly less
convenient for the purpose of
perturbation period and things like that
but it's absolutely possible to discuss
that without whatever yes sure so in
that case
yeah
but what I'm trying to say is that um
I haven't discussed in detail what what
is the the company I mean
the point is that uh it's uh
it's hard to write out the correct I
will tell you
uh it's hard to know what this important
they are into the many you know in
tournament right most of them don't work
and most of them will lead to an
inconsistent varies with the uh
super numerals and you have to know
exactly whether you can buy including
terms sometimes
yes are there issues with their
derivation if we choose for C to go to
Infinity
um
that uh depends
um you could say that you sometimes uh
typically this left hand side is the
field defining that limit in some in the
hospital
thing and this is
fine so we don't like to take that limit
however uh
um we will take elements of
um well later will be interesting
elements where you can take the
imaginary part of field of definitely
sense that that will have some use but
for so far the time people say it's in
real time and that we do not want to
take the time but we will imagine times
yes
I'm gonna come to that next I'm about to
schedule it out please I haven't
discussed that yet
okay so so now let me uh carry on one
more step because so far I haven't
connected this to lagrangement yes and
this is still the hamiltonian uh but uh
but that's just one more step
um okay so uh if H uh DQ
is quadratic
uh
uh for example in our
in this case
like this
but then
obviously and
well this intro looks like a Galaxy in
fact if you stare at it uh it's a it's a
conversation with the slightly awkward
um
uh
coefficient which is uh which is
imaginary
um but we're going to uh not worry about
that too much at the moment we'll come
back to that
um so
um uh if you choose
you know the correct uh Contour
integration
um at least you'll be able to uh to
perform the integral as a Galaxy
integral
um and uh the results of that uh
gaussian integral
um
yeah the result of the Galaxy integral
is uh is going to be well if you think
about some
and that's why let's give you some
network uh and if you have some
additional uh
TV times something else sometimes
um then you can always complete the
square
um and uh uh then you just get uh the
the same uh number where you don't have
to multiply by the e to the exponents
that extreme lines would be back to T so
um
let me just uh write this in your
formula
um so if Pages were not impede we can
integrate
um
uh and then we're going to be left with
digital with the queue uh well
um you have to be a little bit careful
here because
um you know generally uh there's a
there's a factor so let's say your first
time we're not there you just have this
P Squared this question
um there's uh
uh more generally uh if uh this
coefficient here if this work comes
resolution that only depends on Queue
um integrating out the peak by the
gaussian equal will give you a factor
that depends on Q
uh so that factor will be correcting
this measure so I'm going to now use the
notation uh with that with a bracket
just to remind ourselves that
um
that there's some uh correction to the
measure factor and when you iterate that
P if you think about it it's uh you know
this thing is a uh it's not something
that you have to you have to be a little
careful about so for example
um you know the graduate system or or
the piece the cues which are sort of the
canal granites
um there is no uh there's some Freedom
intrusive to kind of components there's
like the sound of Freedom you're truly
in the general it's coordinates I can
rescale Q by factor of two at risk of P
by a factor one-half
in which case uh this measure will stay
the same if I you know your CLP and Q
are but if by individual P this thing is
no longer invariant underestating of Q
by Factor two uh so you have to worry
about it the normalization how this
measure is required but if you get
confused you can always go back to this
expression and remember the narration
and you can recall how this measured
okay anyway so the point is that after
you integral RP uh you have some uh this
measure against a correction and then
you have into that this expression here
uh now
um after continues Square uh LP by the
gaussian so you'll be adapted with uh
this exponent here extremise went back
to uh
DT
equal to the obstacle minus h
that's the thing over there
um but now I'm going to extremise this
with record B so that is said the
derivative of this is equal to zero that
is Q dot is equal to two
now you can take
this quality
this is uh uh sort of the recycling the
inverse Lagana transform that relates to
hamiltonian back to the ground earlier
about this
let's make a problem this
team is the sequel to the LeBron James
right so uh so with that we end up with
a LaGrange form of the pattern that is
we have uh
element of time you build an operator
which is an integral over a q of P equal
to the ACT e to the I over H Bar times
the action this thing this whole thing
is that it says e to the time over H bar
that's correct that's correct
um uh if it's not uh then uh then you
have to you have to worry
um but um
you know all the kind of standard
mechanical systems are of that one uh so
at that level is okay uh but more
generally uh it's it's something
and second question so when when do you
write this modified measured are you
still speaking
um like modified I like some some um
so here you know there's some factors
depends on and for example
whose organization
[Music]
that's right that's right so foreign
and last thing I was wondering on this
is that when we integrated over the
screen how did that resulting up in Kobe
T dot equals DHCP if we didn't
exclusively write that down
uh
wait are you asking uh how do I know
this the worst information
no right
this is just two right I mean uh you
know the result of integrating RP uh up
to this councilman factor
is that it's going to be
minus B squared
this okay so the way you can compute
this is by completing the score you
write this in here as a minus Square
well my question was is that we always
had to do that because
foreign
we always have that or is it or are we
oh no no no no no you see over here uh p
and Q are independent variables right
there's no relationships right so that's
right so the queues and these are
independent variables are integral over
in this in this form so so over here
there's no really
eliminated
and what you can say here is that
you know the result of integrating this
thing in PMP
factor is given by the detail this
exponent
the same thing but just extremise went
back to here
so I'm thinking that this explaining
here and extremising effectively
it's really easy it's just some
quadratic uh functionality and
extremising that would like to be right
the result what is the result of that
well uh well first of all this is what I
mean by distance
I'm taking this object and I I demand
that it's first folded American without
a zero that is Q naught minus
important
uh
because once we integrate
um that's right so so uh yeah
like this I completely square and uh
have this and uh have some individual uh
and now I can always
change variable the feed by shifting a p
by this whatever it's sitting over here
and that becomes standard gaussian
people does that give you whatever
factors
and then I'm back over with this but
here which is the result you get by
let's remind this expression
okay
yes
um if you want to view the pathway or
some kind of fundamental principle uh uh
you know you might think that that
display attention is just some uh
particular way to make sense to you know
new language to recognize the packages
um uh and uh and indeed uh you know if
if we start with just knowing the
lagrangian and we don't know what
hamiltonian is and uh precisely as an
operator uh then uh you know if you
write the path of the world you have to
figure out a way to make precise sense
of it I want to make sense of it is to
do this this realization we'll see that
it's not the only way to make sense of
it there are other ways that are more
useful for product computations
um but whatever way you choose to
realize it uh there might be some
ambiguity for the h bar
that plus
no that that step is is fine but that
doesn't have anything to do with this
ambiguity uh except uh that sometimes if
this coefficient here depends on Q then
you have to worry a little bit about how
you normalize this measure
um we will see uh how this is treated in
practice
um in fact that uh in a way is uh can be
understood also in terms of discounted
costs so that that's uh that's something
we'll understand uh in some examples yes
what exactly are we taking deep feed
like what are we okay that that's a very
good question that's a very good
question there's a side of a hand and I
see that I didn't get away with it uh
um
um so
um if you wish uh yeah so that's any of
the any kind of questions are like that
you always have to go to uh you know
through the regular history where this
integral is actually defined so for
example if you do this then uh then then
you can literally stare at this
expression now you're integrating that
measure energy yeah there's a yes
so that that you don't have it but like
the particular n goes to Infinity right
now we're I guess integrating over hit
the number of differentials which seems
so defined uh uh well you're instructed
to do this tutorial first and then take
into Infinity but that's how the
regulation is supposed to work right uh
and the otherwise you you'll be not
doing anything so so you want to first
uh um this retire in some way so to make
uh this would have a Time variable maybe
uh later we'll see if we can have the
first way transform and and then play
some cut off on the player notes
um that's something else you can do
um and uh after you do that
regularization uh you now have a well
defined in the world then you can
perform anything then hopefully you can
pay the limit back to the end to
Infinity uh and hopefully the results
would make sense and if describes actual
visual system of Interest
uh
uh okay uh I guess I'm out of time
I only managed to go get through half of
it
uh and the the issue is that we probably
have to we don't have to delay the
Commerce because we're gonna uh but what
was it uh
it's good to be it's good to be uh you
know slow and uh and more have more
discussions
okay
thank you
um
[Music]
what's up
um
is
[Music]
so I I take this I thought something
about this here
is
foreign
[Music]
okay uh there are more uh useful
homework yeah we're gonna spend a lot of
time for the rest of this uh
um
[Music]
thank you
injury
um
foreign
[Music]
plus whatever value is at the minimum
so then we so the first part when we
integrate over P minus something squared
the exponential of that respect to P are
constant because it's a calcium
vegetable we just bury that into DQ oh
there's another part that's left over
there
yeah
minimum of the
um
something
yeah